<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: lifestyle | Francesco Tassi]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ftassi.com/blog/categories/lifestyle/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ftassi.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-24T08:34:18+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ftassi.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Francesco Tassi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[time to move again]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ftassi.com/blog/2013/09/23/time-to-move-again/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-23T22:57:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ftassi.com/blog/2013/09/23/time-to-move-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>From the 26th of September we&rsquo;ll move to Las Palmas de Gran Canaria. For how long? Who knows, best case scenario is until April 2014, but we could come back quicker if Monica won&rsquo;t be able to find a decent job down there.</p>

<p>A brand new adventure is about to start and I&rsquo;m quite excited about it, but this is not really the point of this post.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m writing this for 2 main reasons:</p>

<h2>1 &ndash; Nothing&rsquo;s impossible</h2>

<p>Every time (not every, but around 90%) I tell someone that I&rsquo;m leaving the reaction is something like &ldquo;OH man!! You&rsquo;re so lucky, I wish I could do the same&rdquo;.</p>

<p>You know what? I&rsquo;m not that lucky, I&rsquo;m just making this happen, and if you want to do the same you should too. I&rsquo;m not the best at what I do, I&rsquo;m not a rock star, I&rsquo;m not rich and I&rsquo;m not &ldquo;extra&rdquo; anything, I&rsquo;m just a guy and I&rsquo;m doing it, so if you want to, you can do it too.</p>

<p>I guess the first step is knowing what you want, and everything else comes after that.</p>

<h2>2 &ndash; Want to live in Italy for a while ?</h2>

<p>Get in touch with me. I can rent you my place while I&rsquo;m in Spain (or we can plan a home exchange for next year). If you&rsquo;re a developer chances are that you will be able to work and live at my place, &lsquo;cause I was doing it before you ;). I recently built a <a href="http://www.cowo42.com">coworking space</a> with some collegues of mine and you&rsquo;ll be able to use my desk for all the time, working with some of the <a href="http://www.cowo42.com/#coworkers">greatest guys</a> around here.</p>

<p>I guess I don&rsquo;t have to say nothing <a href="http://www.nespresso.com/">about the coffe</a> that you&rsquo;ll find ;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
